- Yes. - Let me have one foot long.
- 要什麼？ - 給我一個長麵包
- Foot long? - Yeah foot long.
- 長麵包？ - 是的
- $1.50. - Do you have a foot long hotdog?
- 一塊五 - 你們家沒有長熱狗麵包麼？
No, we don't.
不好意思沒有
Oh, Man... uhmm I'll just have two regular ones then...
啊偶，厄… 那我就要兩個普通麵包
Yeah, just like that.
對，就像那樣的
Yeah, can I have some Ketchup on that?
對，能不能給我加點番茄醬？
Ketchup?
番茄醬？
Holy shit.
我靠
Fuck... What's happening Alex?
媽的… 亞力克斯，怎麼了？
Hey Lenny, uhm... my mom talked to...
嗨，倫尼，厄… 我媽和…
Yeah, have you seen, have you seen Sage?
嗨，你有沒有 有沒有看到薩奇？
No, but my mom talked to Sage's Mom and told her that...
沒有，但我媽和薩奇的媽媽講過了 跟她說好了
You know, I could go to your house.
你懂的，我能去你家玩
- Whoa! - Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
- 哇！ - 噢！噢！
Excuse me.
麻煩你解釋一下怎麼回事
- Are you there father? - Yes!
- 你是他們的父親？ - 是的！
OK. Well you have some parenting to do.
你得好好管教他們了
Really? OK I have some parenting to do?
真的？ 我需要好好管教他們？
- Yes you do. - Who are you?
- 是的 - 你誰啊？
I am the principal of this school, Mr. Puccio...
我是校長 普喬先生
Puccio?!
普喬？！
I don't think this is a matter for laughter right now...
我覺得現在不是開玩笑的時候
- Let me tell you what happened today. - Alright, I suggest you do that.
- 我講給你聽今天發生什麼事了 - 好的，洗耳恭聽
First of all, Frey assaulted his math teacher.
首先，弗雷打了數學老師
OK, the kid is the size of a two year old,
喂，這孩子塊頭只有這麼大
so I don't know what kind of ruckus he'd be causing in your classroom.
我不知道這麼小的孩子 能在課堂上引起啥騷動
Kids do not assault teachers, OK?
孩子不能打老師，好不好？
And wait let me show you something else.
等等，我給你看另一樣東西
- Take a look at this. - Alright just shut your mouth,
- 看看這個 - 好好，你先別說話
shut up.
閉嘴
Holy shit... This is fucking disgusting.
我靠 這真噁心
Excuse me! Do not use that kind of language here.
不好意思 請你不要說髒話
Do not reprimand me in front of my own kids! Alright?!
別在我孩子面前衝我嚷嚷，懂麼？
Excuse me, that hair came from one of his classmates, Brandon.
不好意思，這些頭髮是 他同班同學布蘭登的
Just calm down for a second, I'd like to hear what happened.
你先冷靜一會兒 讓我聽聽到底怎麼回事
Brandon was beating up Johnny... I don't like that.
當時布蘭登在打約翰尼 我不喜歡他打人
Maybe this would be more productive if you came back with their mother.
我覺得你還是叫他們媽媽 過來一起談談比較好
Alright, C'mon guys.
好，走吧，孩子們
What? What are you doing?
喂，幹嘛跟著我們？
You know we have things to do. Okay?
我們有正事要辦，好麼？
I'm sorry it was nice to see you, you'll see him at school tomorrow.
見到你很高興 你們明天上課再見吧
But wait... But my mom isn't here yet.
可是，等一下… 可是我媽還沒來
No moms, no playdates, nothing today. Okay?
別談媽媽，別談約沒約好 今天什麼都別談，行不行？
- And you? What is this?! - Brandon was teasing.
- 還有你！這是怎麼回事？！ - 布蘭登欺負人！
You know what? Pull his hair! Pull his hair!
你知道痛麼？ 拉他頭髮！
- No. - Pull his hair! Pull it!
- 不要 - 拉他頭髮，拉啊！
You like that? You like how that feels?
你喜歡這樣麼？ 你喜歡被人拉頭髮？
C'mon. That's disgusting!
走，你的行為壞透了
Hey guys! I always wanted a blonde mustache,
看，夥計們！ 我一直夢想長金鬍子
how do I look? Fancy?
我看起來如何？帥麼？
Yeah, that's hilarious. Henny Youngman over here.
是啊，很搞笑 就跟羊村長一樣
How you doing sir? Can you spare some change?
你好麼先生？ 能否請你好心施捨！
How's it going partner?
你怎麼會幹這個？
Trying to make some money, and get something to eat.
我只想掙點小錢 好填飽肚子
- Something to eat? - Yes... Um...
- 要吃東西？ - 是啊
You know a lot of guys act like their vets, and they really not vets.
很多人冒充退伍老兵騙錢的
I was stationed at Fort Jackson... 1968, 101st airborne.
1968年我駐紮在傑克遜堡 在101空降師
- Is that-is that Virginia? - No Columbia, South Carolina.
- 在弗吉尼亞？ - 不，在哥倫比亞，南卡
- The ditches? - Yeah... 10 kills.
- 那次著名的迫降？ - 是的，十個人犧牲了
Tell you what we're gonna do, I'm just gonna 20 dollars in my pocket,
實話告訴你吧 我只帶了20塊
so I can get home, but I'll be back to check on you though man.
所以我先回家拿錢 等一下再回來找你
Hey! I won't be here! I'll be in a hotel somewhere and I'll be eating.
嘿，過一會兒我就不在這兒了 我肯定在哪個飯店大吃一頓
It's on you brother, you're talking to a fellow vet.
隨便你，兄弟 我也是個老兵
Thank you.
謝謝
- Has anyone seen Frey? - Nope.
- 有沒有人看到弗雷？ - 沒有
Alright, I'm sure he'll catch up with us...
好吧，相信他能趕上我們
- Hey Alex, what time is your bed time? - Um, 8. I like it, it's early.
- 嘿亞歷克斯，你一般幾點睡覺？ - 恩，八點，早睡早起身體好
Really? Sage tell him what time you go to bed.
真的？薩奇，告訴他你幾點睡的
- Eleven. - See, because he's a grown up, that's why.
- 十一點 - 看到沒，他是個大人了，所以睡得晚
You must be tired when you wake up!
你早上醒來肯定很累
Spare some change?
給點錢吧！
Sorry man, ask this guy, he's the bread winner.
對不起，你問他要吧 他是掙錢養家的
- Young man, spare some change? - We're in the middle of a conversation.
- 小伙子，給點錢吧！ - 我們正在討論呢
I... Uh... Have to use that round...
我…我要上那個圓圓的
There's water in it that you urinate in.
你在堶惕縉羲漕滬
- Toilet! It's in there! - Bathroom. I forgot the name.
- 廁所！就在那兒 - 洗手間，我忘記怎麼說了
You're addressing the wrong guy, this is the bank...
你問錯人了 他才是老闆
Show him what you've got.
給他看看你有啥
Don't give it to him, I said show it to him.
別給他 我讓你給他看看
I bet you got some money in your pocket. I bet you got some.
我賭你口袋埵鹵 我知道的
Hey! He some money, he gave you all that right?
嘿，給我點錢吧 他肯定都給你了
You got some money in your pockets! I bet you do.
你口袋埵鹵 我敢打賭
Look, you don't want them to see you looking bad like that, c'mon on?
你不想在小孩面前失了面子吧 給點兒吧！
Look man. I'm playing with my kids, you asked for money.
我正陪小孩玩的歡 你卻問我要錢
We don't have any. Just a little distance, alright?
我們沒錢給你 離我們遠點，好麼？
- Good luck. - But I've been sitting on my ass all day!
- 祝你好運 - 可我在這兒坐了一整天
Well I've been on my feet all day man!
朋友，我已經站了一整天
Alright, c'mon. Forget the money, c'mon guys! Forget it!
好吧，走吧，別管錢了 走吧孩子們，別管了
Hold on to my belt loops.
抓住我的袢帶
I can't see Sage! Are you holding onto my belt loops?
我看不見薩奇！ 你們抓住袢帶沒？
Hey Buddy?
你好啊！
What's shaking buddy?
什麼東西在搖啊？
This is for real...
這回玩真的…
This one counts...
這局算數了…
- So the score is 10 - 0. - What is it? 0 - 0?
- 比分是10比0 - 什麼？0比0？
Just play!
別管了，打吧！
Shoot it! Shoot it!
打它！打它！
Aww, Swiss Cheese... Guys, that's pathetic.
噢，防守漏洞百出 孩子們，打得真菜
I'm Serving, I'm Serving.
我來發球，我來發球！
Alright, this is going to be even more pathetic.
好吧，那會打得更爛
I got it! I got it!
我來接，我來接！
Whoa! Whoa! That's how someone gonna get hurt. Hey, hey!
停，停！ 這樣會受傷的，喂！
Give me the ball.
把球給我！給我！
What is this the time out corner?
這是幹嘛？ 面壁思過？
Alright, I'll play by myself.
好吧，那我一個人打！
Whoa he's back...
他回場上了
Alright well that's what happens when you've been a bad boy...
你們一做錯事情
...you go to the time out corner... Is that what your mom does?
就去角落罰站 這是老媽教的？
Shut up.
閉嘴
- 55. - Show me! Show me!
- 55斤 - 稱給我看！
Guys! Oh God!
兒子！我靠！
Oh... now we have revenge! Now revenge of Lorenzo.
現在反攻開始！ 洛倫佐的復仇！
Revenge!
復仇！
Alright guys let go, I can't get up.
好了兒子，快放手！ 我起不來了
Come on, stop guys, I'm not kidding. Guys let go of me!
快停手，兒子，我不是開玩笑！ 孩子們放開我！
Pile on! Pile on!
壓上來！壓上來！
Get 'em off me!
放我出去！
- You're suffocating him! - Alright guys seriously get up.
- 你們快悶死他了！ - 聽話，快起來吧！
- He's holding us! - That's not possible!
- 他抓著我們！ - 起不來！
They're holding me, they're holding me!
是他們，他們抓著我！
Alright, OK, make 'em some breakfast, guys go get some breakfast.
好了好了，去給他們做點早飯 孩子們，起來吃飯咯！
Off the bed! Go!
快起床！
- Go buddy go! - A whole lotta nothing.
- 走吧！ - 什麼都沒有
Off you go, sorry buddy.
起來，不好意思
- What is this your feeding the kids? - I don't know?
- 你準備給孩子吃啥？ - 不知道
Look I brought some other stuff...
我帶了一些吃的過來
and the guy at the supermarket you know what he said?
你知不知道超市堛漱H怎麼說…
He said that one out of every million boxes has a very...
他說，每一百萬箱
special prize in it.
有一個中大獎的機會
Very special prize in it alright. You guys want to empty it out?
很特別的大獎 你們想不想把它吃光？
You want to empty it? Open it up, open it up.
想不想？ 打開，打開吧！
On the table.
倒在桌上
Shoot!
哇偶！
A salamander!
一隻蠑螈！蠑螈！
Look at it!
看！
Oh... my... god. Let me see this.
我的天 給我看看！
- That's incredible! - It's alive!
- 真不可思議！ - 它還是活的！
That is incredible! Oh my god, seats guys.
太不可思議了！ 天啊，孩子們坐好！
Here sit down. Incredible! Look at it's head, look at it shaking!
坐好，太不可思議了！ 看它的頭，它還在動！
Oh wait, let me go find something bigger,
等一下，我去拿個大點的東西裝！
or I'm gonna get a little home or something for it okay.
要麼我給它做個小窩
Can you put it in my hands I'll be safe with him.
能不能把它放我手上 我不會傷害它的
I think the first thing we got to do is we got to get a home for it.
我覺得我們首先得給它找一個家
Check this guy out!
看看它！
Oh my god, look at his head shaking.
天啊，看它的頭搖得！
Look at that... you can see his digestive system,
看，你還能看到它的大便
maybe that's just dirt. This is incredible guys.
可能只是塵土 真不可思議！
Check it out guys. What do we use for gravel?
討論一下，孩子們 我們拿什麼當石頭？
We got this.
就這個！
- Actually you know what. - No, that's some of our food.
- 其實… - 不要，那是吃的！
Oh my god, what is he doing?
天啊，他在幹嘛？
Don't make it too wet.
別搞太濕！
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Not on the floor.
喂！喂！ 別讓它到地板上！
Hey! Hey! Hey!
喂！
If this thing gets in the walls, I don't know what would happen.
如果這傢伙爬到牆上去 我也拿它沒辦法
Here let me help, let me help.
讓我來！讓我來！
- I got it. Stop, stop. - Look Lenny I got the Lizard!
- 我抓住了，放手！ - 倫尼，我抓住這蠑螈的！
OK, this is not a... Competition. We're all here to share the lizard.
好，這又不是競爭 我們共有這只蠑螈
- It smells! - First thing we're gonna do...
- 好臭！ - 首先我們要…
- Stop hogging it! - On the table. Hogging it?!
- 別想獨佔它！ - 討論…獨佔？！
- First of all it's not yours! - Silence! Silence!
- 首先這不是你一個人的！ - 安靜！安靜！
The one thing we can do without removing it
除了亂動它
and freaking it out, because now it needs to adjust to a new home...
或者嚇壞它 因為它還不適應新家
is name him...
我們可以做件事 是給它取個名字
Can I show you something in the bathroom?
能不能來看看衛生間堛漯F西？
Just be gentle with him. Hey, Lenny!
對它溫柔點 倫尼，過來！
...he'll swallow. Alright, alright.
它會吃東西的… 來了來了
- What? - What was that in there?
- 怎麼了？ - 剛在那兒你什麼意思？
What was that, you just like slapped my hand away like that.
什麼意思 你剛剛就這樣拍掉我的手
The kids, the kids are outside, okay,
孩子們在外面呢
I don't even know what you're talking about.
我都不知道你在說什麼
Or Bob.
叫鮑勃呢？
Hi spots, no Bob's too normal, I like spots.
你好啊小斑，鮑勃太普通了 我喜歡小斑
Spots, okay, spots.
小斑，好吧，就叫小斑
I want commitment from you two, bed time... Shake on it.
你們要跟我保證馬上睡覺 拍一下我的手！
Okay, here we go, we're gonna make you disappear.
好的，我們開始 我可以讓你消失
Alright the magic words are presto magic. You guys ready?
咒語是「波若波羅密」 知道沒？
- And make us come back. - Well, first things first.
- 要把我們變回來 - 先把你們變走
Alright... one... two... Presto!
好的，一，二，波若
Magic!
波羅密！
Oh my god, this is incredible they're gone.
天啊，太不可思議了 你們竟然消失了！
I'm going to the movies.
我要去放電影了
Why don't you go talk to her?
為什麼不去搭訕她？
I bet she likes smart guys.
我猜她比較喜歡聰明帥哥
- Get her, get her, get her. - Excuse me!
- 把她，把她，把她！ - 勞駕！
- Louder!
- 大聲點！
Excuse me! I'm sorry, um, hey.
麻煩您，厄……、
I'd like to buy a drink for the girl over by the chalk board.
我想請吧檯上那姑娘喝杯酒
Which girl are you talking about?
哪一個？
The one right there at the end of the bar,
就吧檯盡頭那個
in the white... just a whiskey like I have.
穿白衣服那個 給她一杯威士忌，和我一樣
- You made the right choice. - Shut the fuck up.
- 你邁出了正確一步 - 給我閉嘴
You gotta look at her.
你得盯著她看
Good morning. What's shaking?
早上好 我心跳得好厲害
How are you?
你好嗎？
I'm fine.
我很好
I presume I should split.
我想我該走了
You can hang out for a bit, because I got to pack my stuff and get ready
你可以再待一會兒 我要收拾一下東西
because I am going to go upstate today.
因為今天我要去鄉下
Far fucking out! I fucking love it up there.
真他媽遠！ 我就喜歡這兒！
I love upstate so much.
我可喜歡鄉下了
I haven't been outside the city in I think 4 years, you know.
我四年沒離開這地方了
Okay...
好吧
Alright guys, up and at 'em, up and at 'em.
起床吧，小懶蟲們
Guess what!? We're going on vacation. We're going on vacation!
知道麼，我們要去度假！
- No! No! - Up! Up!
- 不起！不起！ - 趕緊起來！
- We're going on vacation! - It's the weekend!
- 我們要去度假！ - 今天是禮拜天！
- We're going upstate. - Open the can of nuts for me
- 我們去鄉下度假 - 給我開一下罐頭
Fantastic. That's hilarious.
很好玩的
We have fifteen minutes to get our stuff together, we're going upstate!
有十五分鐘收拾東西 我們要去鄉下玩
- I don't want to go on vacation! - Alright, come on.
- 我不想去！ - 別說了，快起！
- Pack your bags guys. - I don't have any bags!
- 收拾好自己的包 - 我沒有旅行包！
Use your school bags, just dump em out.
那就用書包 把東西倒出來就好
We're going upstate guys! We're going upstate!
我們要去鄉下度假了，兒子！ 去度假！
We have fifteen minutes! Up! Up! Up! Up! Up!
我們只有十五分鐘！ 趕緊趕緊趕緊起！
Just pack your bags man.
收拾好包！
Dump 'em! Dump 'em!
把它們倒空！
I'm dumping 'em, I'm dumping 'em.
我在倒，在倒呢！
Do we need bathing suits?
要不要帶泳衣？
- It was supposed to be a nice ride up... - It is going to be a nice ride.
- 這會是一個歡快的旅程麼？ - 這會是一個歡快的旅程！
No, no that's not what I'm asking, your not listening.
不，我不是問這個 你沒在聽我說話
- No I was talking... - No, let me finish, let me finish.
- 不，我在說… - 讓我說完，讓我說完…
The guy called you, and you just decided, that oh,
這傢伙拜託你 然後你就決定
it would be a good thing to do that, I'm going with my boyfriend out
啊，我和我男朋友 去鄉下度假的時候
to the countryside, but let me tag along this guy.
捎上這個傢伙 這主意真不錯
What were you thinking!
你究竟在想什麼！
He was feeling kind of overwhelmed by the city
他厭倦了城市堛漸肮
so I thought it would be a nice thing to do if we brought...
所以我覺得帶上他一起 算是做了件好事
We were supposed to be a nice weekend.
我們本來能過個不錯的週末的
- We are going to have a nice time. - Yeah, sure!
- 我們本來能玩得很開心的 - 是啊，當然！
And while where having a good time...
當我們玩得很開心的時候…
Yeah, the three of us having a good time...
是啊，我們三個人會玩得很開心…
...well my plans were having a good time me and you.
…我設想的是咱們倆的二人世界
- Not the three of us having a good time. - We cans till have a good time.
- 而不是三個人一起玩！ - 這並不影響我們倆
Alright, out.
好好，出來
- There he is. There he is... - Oh my god...
- 他出來了… - 噢天啊
- Hey! - Hey, Lenny?
- 嗨！ - 嗨！倫尼？
- What's happening? - How are you?
- 怎麼回事？ - 你好！
This is the super of my building and this is his son peanut...
這位是我房子堛熄W人 這是他的兒子花生先生
They have been helping me carry my bags. Thanks guys.
他們幫我拿包下來的 多謝夥計們！
- Lookidy, lookidy. - Introduce yourselves guys.
- 看看這倆小可愛 - 你們自我介紹一下
- I'm Sage. - I'm Robert... Hello.
- 我是薩奇 - 我是羅伯特，你好！
That's Frey and these guys are so excited.
他是弗雷 他們知道要旅遊都很興奮
Come one, come on.
過來，過來
- That's Aaron. - Hey, Aaron, Lenn...
- 這是亞倫 - 你好，亞倫，倫尼
- Hey, Lenny, how are you? - Thank you so much!
- 幸會！倫尼 - 真太感謝你了
God, their so excited.
天啊，他們太興奮了
- I'm in the middle, I'm in the middle. - Hey guys...
- 我坐中間，我坐中間 - 喂夥計！
What's happening man? You mind if we throw our stuff in the back?
怎麼了朋友？ 介不介意我們把東西放後面？
- Yeah sure, don't fuck up the rug though. - What? Excuse me.
- 是啊，別弄壞我的地圖 - 什麼？
Nothing, nothing.
沒什麼，沒啥
"Now I was so frightened, that I'll tell you but I have to.
"現在我很害怕告訴你， 但是我別無選擇
I screamed and rode away and lost my hook line and bate too."
我尖叫著跑開了 掉了鉤線 失去了力氣"
- I thought this was supposed to rhyme. - I had no idea he had kids.
- 我覺得這句應該是押韻 - 我不知道他有孩子
Crazy?! Your loco! You're more than crazy.
瘋狂？！你就是個神經病 說你瘋狂就是侮辱瘋狂
Forget about crazy. Don't even approach the subject of crazy.
別說瘋不瘋狂了 最好提都別提
The guy comes in with his kids...
那傢伙和他孩子一起來…
Oh, wait guys! Check it out! I got a traveling tape for us.
噢，等一下 看，我帶了盤磁帶
Good.
很好
- Can we put it on? - I'm telling you this thing...
- 能不能放一下？ - 我跟你說…
Guys! No music in the car please, really I get allergic to music,
車上不准放音樂 我對音樂很反感
I can't stand music while I'm driving,
開車的時候我受不了音樂在耳邊
I can't concentrate on the road and that's about it.
那樣我不能專心開車 僅此而已
- I have to concentrate on the road. - Your allergic to music?
- 我得集中精力開車 - 你對音樂反感？
Right.
是的
Awesome.
真奇怪
Whose the witness?
誰來做證人？
Sage you see it? OK? Don't forget it.
薩奇你看到了吧？ 記住它
- Alright, name that flavor. - Blue raspberry.
- 好的，說說什麼味道？ - 藍樹莓
What! You cheated! You little runt.
什麼！你作弊了！ 你個小壞蛋！
- Yeah you cheated. - How would you know so fast.
- 是的你作弊了 - 你怎麼這麼快就知道了？
Alright, who wants to, what do we got thumb war?
好的，誰想要玩拇指戰爭
One, two, three, four.
一二三四
"Oh, say can you see,
"噢，說出你看到的
by the dawns early lights we are proud to be here..."
我們很自豪能站在這 在破曉的晨光"
Wait, you skipped the whole middle part, wait you skipped like four lines.
等等，你漏掉了中間的部分 一共漏了四行
Start over. One, two, three, four.
重新開始 一二三四
"Oh say can you see..."
"噢，說出你看到的…"
Guys can you just shut up for a second!
夥計們，能不能消停兒一會兒！
I'm sorry man, I shouldn't yell. I'm sorry for this.
對不起，我不應該吼的 對不起
Hey, hey!
嘿嘿！
- Wake up. - Yeah.
- 醒一醒 - 哦
You have to drive man, I'm totally tired.
你來開會兒車吧 我累死了
Take a nap, man, pull over, we'll all take a nap.
休息一下吧 停一下車，我們都休息會兒
I'm not going to pull over, we have to get there, so you have to drive.
我不會停車，我們要直開到那兒 所以你來開吧
Just pull over, man, we'll all take a nap.
朋友，停一下車吧 我們都要睡一會兒
What's happening?
怎麼了？
Just go back to sleep.
繼續睡吧
What are you doing?
你幹嘛？
You want me to drive the car?
要我開車？
No, he has to drive. He has to drive.
不，他來開 他必須開車
Just pull him, he has to drive.
把他弄醒 讓他來開
Aaron?
亞倫？
"Winter snow that melts, April rain,
"冬天雪融化，四月雨飄揚
Oh, darling in my heart,
噢，親愛的，在我心中
you’ll always will remain,
你永遠都在
when summer turns to fall.
夏去秋來
As summer turns to fall..."
夏去秋來啊…"
- I want that one. - OK, this one is giant.
- 我要那一根 - 好的，這根很粗
You broke my stick.
你把我的棍子弄斷了
Come on guys, we're leaving, come on.
過來孩子們 我們要走了
We've got to get to the boat. Come on!
我們要去船上了 快來吧
Hang on I gotcha.
我追上你了
- Here, give me your hand. - Come on guys...
- 來，把你手給我 - 跟上，夥計們
- Come on. - Come on... Firas!
- 趕快 - 趕快，弗奡窗I
Firas!
弗奡窗I
Firas, hi man.
弗奡窗A你好！
- Come on and let me introduce you. - Hello.
- 來，我給你介紹一下 - 你好
That's a very good friend, that's the guy who's going to bring the boat.
他是我的好朋友 是這次的掌舵手
That's Frey... This is Firas.
這是弗雷，這是弗奡
- Your not gonna go water skiing? - It's 50 degrees outside.
- 你們不去滑水麼？ - 才50度（華氏）
It's hot, the sun is up.
天變暖了，太陽出來了
It's warm.
很溫暖
The summer is not over.
夏天還沒結束
Excellent. Beautiful.
很好，很漂亮
- I got him, I got him man. - Help them in the boat.
- 我抓住他了，抓住了 - 帶他們上船
Hey, I got them.
好，我抓住他們了
Go ahead.
進去
Life vests on, oh great good going, grab it.
穿上救生衣 好的，抓牢
- How do you do this? - Here I'll tell you,
- 這個怎麼弄？ - 我馬上教你
you always have to sit on the boat, don't stand up...
你們得一直坐在船上 不能站起來
Alright guys, I'll pick you up in what, two hours OK.
好了孩子們 我過兩個小時來接你們
- No! - What?!
- 不！ - 什麼?!
Check him out!
看看他！
Come on!
加油！
Oh, he's up!
噢，他飛起來了！
Faster! Go Faster!
快點，滑快點！
What do you guys think?
你們覺得如何？
Look at what he's doing?
看看他滑得！
Hey, check it out guys. Sage, Sage.
嘿，看看這傢伙 薩奇，薩奇！
- Hi baby! - Over here, over here, I need some help.
- 嗨寶貝 - 過來幫我一下
Alright, what do you want me to catch for dinner tonight.
好的，你希望我抓點什麼 當今天的晚飯？
- Salmon. - Salmon, alright.
- 大馬哈魚 - 大馬哈魚，好的
I learned this in the army.
我在部隊媥ЛL一手
Anchor me! I got one! I got one!
崇拜我吧！ 我抓住一條了！
It got away, it got away. Hang on.
它跑掉了，它跑了 繼續
We're still going for salmon?
我們繼續抓大馬哈魚？
Alright hold onto my waste.
好的，抓住我的腰
Alright guys, lower me, lower me.
好的孩子們 把我往下放一點，往下
Pull me in! Pull me in I got it!
把我拉回去 我抓到了
Ah, it got away! It got away!
啊，它又跑走了！
Holy shit, hey Firas! What is that?
我靠，嘿弗奡窗I 那是什麼？
That's Terry.
那是特
Far Fucking out!
真酷！
Mirand...
米蘭達…
What do you want, Sage?
什麼事兒，薩奇？
Ewww!
惡！
This is sticky and ugly.
又土又醜
Sorry, please take out a sheet of paper.
請大家拿出一張紙
Um, sit down please Fletcher, come on guys.
弗蘭徹請坐下 孩子們趕快
Get out a piece of paper, let's do a morning message.
請拿出一張紙 我們要做一個早練
Sit down please, let's start off with that one.
請坐下 我們從那道題開始做
Let's get a subtraction problem in there.
我們來做減法
I'm very sorry guys.
我很抱歉小朋友們
Alright guys, the other day we were working on this problem,
孩子們 我們有一天做過一道題
and a lot of you guys had some difficulty with it.
你們中好多人覺得比較難
We tried to tally it up. It's 11+8.
我們試試把它們加起來 11加8等於多少？
OK you guys ready for this?
你們準備好答題了麼？
What the heck?
什麼鬼東西？
It's on your back!
在你背上！
Benny, Benny, come on do it. Let's do it.
本，你過來做這題 大家一起做
You got this. You got it.
你算出來了，答對了
Write it, write down there.
把答案寫下來 就寫這兒
What's the answer? You got it, you can do it.
答案是什麼？ 你算出來了，你行的
Did you get it right? Guys, did he get it right?
你算對了麼？ 小朋友們，他算對了麼？
Yes!
對了！
Come on Tristin.
快點，特奡等
Yo Sage.
喂，薩奇
You want to spray Miranda with fart spray?
你想不想用臭味劑噴米蘭達？
Smell it. See what she'll smell like.
聞一聞 看她聞了什麼反應
So are you with us or not.
你是不是我們一夥的啊？
I mean I'd love to but I don't wanna. I got in a lot of trouble already.
我想，但是我不會去噴她 我現在已經夠麻煩的了
Fine by me!
那我去噴她
I'll trail behind and see what...
我跟著你去看看會怎樣…
It's gonna be the laughing of a life time.
我會讓你愉快終身的
William, can I interest you in some CD's.
威廉，你對CD感不感興趣？
No, no, no, they're only five dollars a piece.
不不不，只要五塊錢一張
Yo my friend, you like Bill Withers?
朋友，你喜歡張學友麼？
You a reggae man? Yo reggae man.
你唱搖滾的麼？ 雷鬼
Hey Mr. Ice cream, yo!
嘿，冰激凌哥！
Let me help you.
我來幫你
- Slow down, how you doing? - I'm alright,
- 等一下，你好麼？ - 我很好
- I don't have any money man. - Money! What do you mean money?
- 朋友，我沒錢 - 錢！我不是那種人
Hey don't fucking touch me, I don't have any money all right.
喂別碰我 我身上一分錢都沒有
You like Bill Withers?
你喜歡張學友麼？
Come on, come on, you look like a Bill Wither man.
看看嘛 你看起來像是喜歡張學友的
How about this, Jeffery Lewis? Hold on come here.
那周傑倫呢？ 等一下看看吧！
Are they for free? I told you I don't have any money.
免費的麼？ 我跟你講了我沒錢
You don't have any money, how did you buy that ice cream.
你沒錢怎麼買那麼多冰激凌？
Here take some bread.
拿些麵包去吃吧
Take some bread? Who the fuck do you think your talking to jackass?
拿些麵包去吃？ 你以為你在打發乞丐啊！
- Here try this. - Alright, game over, game over.
- 讓你嘗嘗這個的厲害 - 好好，我投降
OK. That's cool, everything's cool. Hurry up man.
我喜歡你的識相 快點拿錢出來
- You want to hold the fucking cones? - Yeah I'll hold the fucking cones.
- 你要這些冰激凌？ - 是啊我要冰激凌！
You think this is a fucking game. You think this is a fucking game, man.
你他媽覺得很好玩麼？ 很好玩麼，啊？
- No, I don't. - Yeah?
- 不，不是 - 是嗎？
You want to see those people your buying that ice cream for.
你還想不想見到你給買冰激凌的人了？
- Here. - Everything's cool bro.
- 給你 - 幹得好，兄弟
- Can't I just by some CD's? - There ain't no CD's in there.
- 那能不能把CD給我？ - 鬼跟你講有CD的！
I'll hold on to you, Sage.
我會上去抓住你，薩奇
Hey guys! Guys!
嘿，小伙子們
What's happenin'? Sorry, I'm late.
孩子們，玩啥呢？ 對不起我來晚了
Where's the ice cream!?
冰激凌呢？
You know what?
你知道麼？
I had ice cream and if you kick me like that you're not getting anything.
我帶了冰激凌，但是如果你像那樣踢我 就什麼都吃不到
Can we have a play-date with Djoume?
我們能不能和杜約姆約一天一起玩？
- Oh, give me a break. Guys. - You wanna go to play?
- 噢，讓我喘口氣吧，小傢伙 - 你想不想去玩？
- Yeah. - Please.
- 想 - 求你了
It's not a good idea.
這樣不太好
- Listen guys. - Please.
- 聽著，孩子們 - 求你了
Hey. Listen to me. Calm down.
嘿，冷靜一點聽我說
Alright. It was a rotten day today.
行了，今天出門不利
We're going home, we're calming down, alright?
我們回家，大家冷靜一下好麼？
Yeah, but that's because your making me tense... you know...
是，但是你讓我如此緊張的好麼…
Alright.
好
I was in a great mood when I dialed the phone.
我打這個電話時心情還是很好的
You know, my intention was to call you
我的目的是
and share with you some very pleasant news.
和你分享一些愉快的事情
We went upstate, you know...
我們去鄉下玩了
Yes UP-state, does that sound like I crossed state lines?
是的，去-鄉-下 聽起來好像我出國了一樣？
Look, you know what, you're doing it right now.
你現在這麼做…
You're doing it right now,
你這麼做…
and I don't know what your going to achieve with this.
我不知道你究竟想幹什麼
What? Do you want me to just not call you and give you updates?
什麼？ 你想知道我們每天幹了什麼 卻不想讓我打電話過來？
You know I wish I had a...
你知不知道我有多想…
Right, I'm gonna start tape recording these conversations.
好好，我要把這通電話錄下來
Because I'll rewind it and play it back, and that's not how you said it.
然後反覆回放 你之前不是這麼說的
That's not how you say it.
你之前不是這麼說的，好嗎？
Yeah, they can hear us right now.
是啊，他們現在能聽到我們講話
Keep going. Keep going. Keep going.
繼續，繼續啊
Hey kids, hey guys. Say hi to your mom.
孩子們 跟你們媽問個好
- Hi mom. - Alright, they're looking at me right now.
- 媽媽 - 好吧，他們現在正看著我
Yeah. No that's you, you are perpetuating this.
看吧，不，是你 是你讓他們記住這些的
You know what, you have two choices right now.
知道嗎？ 你現在有兩個選擇
One is you continue acting the way your acting
第一個選擇，你繼續我行我素
and you watch me blow my top. Or two I hang up on you.
對我頤指氣使 第二種就是掛電話
Alright you got five... one. Alright goodbye,
給你五…一… 好的，再見
you made your choice, goodbye.
你已經做出選擇了，再見
You see that guys? You see that? That was awesome, huh.
看到沒孩子們？看到沒？ 真棒哈，呵呵
Now I'm mad!
現在我已經瘋了！
- Hello? - Hey Lenny, open!
- 誰啊？ - 喂倫尼，開門！
Alright guys...
來了
- Hey what's shakin' Salvie. - Hi guys? How are you Lee?
- 什麼風把賽爾維吹來了？ - 嗨大家好，你好麼倫尼？
Come on in, you picked a fantastic time.
進來吧，你可真會挑時間
- Salvie! Salvie. - Hi kids, how are you guys?
- 賽爾維，賽爾維！ - 孩子們你們好啊！
You guys remember Salvie... look's like he's got something.
你們還記得賽爾維麼？ 他好像帶了好東西
This better be flattering.
你們最好拍拍他馬屁
So I arrived there. They were fighting, bloody.
我到了那兒
- Who was fighting? - My brother and his wife.
- 誰在打架？ - 我弟和他老婆
- Your brother lives in Brooklyn? - He lives in Brooklyn.
- 你弟弟住在布魯克林？ - 他住在布魯克林
He was bloody fighting with his wife.
他當時和他老婆打得頭破血流的
- Today? - Tonight.
- 今天？ - 今晚
Your brother lives in Brooklyn right now?
你弟弟現在住在布魯克林？
- Yes, yes. He is living there. - I didn't know this.
- 是的，他住那兒 - 我都不知道
So anyway, I could not stay there.
不管怎樣，他家我是待不下去了
- So I went to that motel... - Let me see what you got here.
- 所以我去住汽車旅館… - 讓我看看你帶了啥過來
So this is supposed to be me?
這是我？
There we go, fantastic.
看過了，挺夢幻的
- Here's some gum. - Fantastic.
- 這邊還有口香糖 - 不錯
...everybody was blind in that hotel. Do you understand?
那家旅館堛漱H都是瞎的 你知道我什麼意思麼？
Which part? Salvie, I'm sorry. I'm trying to follow you.
你講到哪兒了賽爾維？ 不好意思我沒在聽
Oh my god. Let me eat these kids and forget about this story.
天啊，別管那件事兒了
What?
什麼？
And by now your blood will be sweet. Because I eat kids. I eat kids!
你們的血肯定是甜的
I will eat both of you.
我要把你們倆都吃了
Salvie.
賽爾維！
Salvie's a monster!
賽爾維是大怪獸！
Oh my god.
天啊
Do you mind Lee if I eat one of them.
倫尼，你介意我吃掉他們中一個麼？
You stay like that. Just lie down and I will walk on you,
你就那樣躺著，躺在那兒我來踩你
but keep your stomach very strong. I beg-
請把你肚子鼓硬一點 我要…
No! Him first!
不，先踩他！
I will begin with you now. Are you able?
我先從你開始，好麼？
- Tell me. Are you able? - Yes. I think.
- 告訴我，你可以麼？ - 我想可以
Help me... I can't...
救命…我不能…
No! Stop! Get off! You're hurting him! Get off!
不要！快停下來！你傷到他了！
What the fuck is going on here? Are you alright?
他媽的怎麼回事？ 你還好吧？
Is he alright? Are you kidding or not?
他還好吧？ 你是不是在開玩笑？
- He's not. - Alright, he's joking with me.
- 他沒有 - 他和我開玩笑呢
- Yeah, he's smiling.
- 他在開玩笑，瞧他在笑呢
He's not. He's stepping on us.
他開玩笑！他踩我們！
Stepping on him!? How would you like it if we stepped on you?
踩他？我踩你你會怎麼樣啊？
Alright. Fun time is done. Time for bed. It's a school night.
好了，別再玩了 上床時間到了，明天還要上學
I am strong enough for that.
我夠強壯
Enough games, enough candy. It's bed time, people.
吃夠玩夠了，該上床睡覺了
- Pizza man! - Quiet!
- 你拿不到！ - 安靜點兒！
Come and get it, you morons.
過來拿啊，你個笨蛋！
Don't make me come over there, I'm not kidding.
別讓我過去，我不是開玩笑的
Get in bed.
去床上睡覺
- Get back in bed. - Fine.
- 回床上睡覺 - 哦
You know what? I'm gonna take all that candy
知道麼？我會把糖都拿走
and I'm gonna flush it down the toilet, how about that?
然後都衝到廁所堨h，怎麼樣？
In bed. L-
睡覺去！
"It's very fond indeed of English school children,
"我很喜歡英國學校的孩子
they have a nice inky booky flavor.
他們有強烈的好學精神…
Perhaps I will change my mind and go to England with them..."
可能我要改變主意和他們一起去英國…"
"You is disgusting!" Said the BFG. "And you is an insult
「你真噁心！」 好心眼兒巨人說
to the Giant Peoples!" Shouted blood Bottler.
「你的存在對巨人國來講是一個恥辱」 喝血巨人大喊！
Does anyone know the Capital of Oklahoma?
有沒有人知道俄克拉何馬州的首府？
Frey.
弗雷
What was the question?
問題是什麼？
- Ben. - Oklahoma City.
- 本 - 俄克拉荷馬城
Oklahoma City, well done.
俄克拉荷馬城，答得很好
Class, this is a perfect example of what happens when you pay attention
同學們，你們有沒有認真聽課
and when you don't pay attention, okay. Very well done Ben.
從這件事上就能看出來 本做得很好
Alright Rick, Rick, you're all threaded up
好了，堜_ 帶子我都給你裝好了
and set to go man, you hit screen in ten minutes, okay?
可以播了 過十分鐘按一下屏幕，行麼？
I'm threaded up? What do you mean? No, no, aren't you working tonight.
帶子都給我裝好了？什麼意思？ 不，今晚不是你上班麼？
No. I am not working tonight, you are working tonight.
不，今晚不是我上班 是你
- Oh, no, no. - No, no, what?
- 噢不 - 為啥？
- Your on the schedule. - No.
- 今天輪到你上班 - 不
First of all I am not on the schedule, and second of all we agreed to this,
首先我不在工作表上 其次我們達成過協議
you are working tonight, I have to pick up my kids.
今晚你工作 我去接孩子
I just came in to drop off the log.
我只是進來放工作表的
Alright, don't fuck with me man. Okay, I have to pick up my kids.
行了，別再難為我了 好不好，我要去接孩子
I can't, remember we had that conversation, I have things to do...
我不行，記不記得我跟你講過今晚有事
Alright. Alright. Listen to me. Listen to me.
行，行，聽我說，聽我說
- I have no flexibility here. - Neither do I.
- 我沒時間了 - 我也沒有
- I'm already late. - I can't help ya, I got to go.
- 我已經遲到了 - 我幫不了你，我得走了
Listen to me. Please.
聽我說，求你了
No, no, no, your staying, this is your night we talked about this.
不不不，你待在這兒吧 今晚你工作，我們說好的
- Next time. Next time. - Alright this movie's not gonna be run.
- 下次，下次 - 沒人放電影了
I gotta go.
我要走了
Where you going?
你去哪兒？
The kids are with their dad this week, and you know,
孩子們這個禮拜跟著他們爸爸，而且
I'm on vacation, I'm supposed to have this time off.
我正在度假 這時候您不該找我
Unfortunately my last interaction with their dad was not very positive.
不幸的是上次我和他們爸爸 溝通得並不愉快
- Hello?! - Your here! Finally.
- 你好？！ - 你終於來了
I apologize, unreservedly.
對不起
- What are you doing here? - You guys, I love you.
- 你在這兒幹嘛？ - 兒子，我愛你們
- Mr. Puccio, had to call me.
- 普喬先生沒辦法了，才打電話給我
- You have no business being here. - These are my kids...
- 這兒不是你該來的 - 他們是我孩子
what am I gonna do leave them standing here waiting for you...
我怎麼能拋下他們 讓他們站這兒等你
I apologize, something came up at work. OK, but you know what this is my time.
對不起，我工作時出了點狀況 但是，現在是我的時間你知道麼？
You're not responsible enough to be here to pick them up.
你這種「接」法未免太不負責任了
Alright, have been told in advance...
我之前告訴過他們…
...that if daddy has an emergency, their going to sit and wait,
…如果爸爸有急事 他們就坐那兒等等
there's no danger in that.
因為不會有什麼危險的
They cannot be standing here, and the school is responsible,
他們不能就坐在那兒， 學校很負責任
and I am responsible and obviously you don't think it's a big deal!
我也很負責 可顯然你不覺得這是個大問題
Okay, you're in charge of the school stuff.
好好，他們在學校的事都歸你管
You're right! I am in charge, you obviously can't be trusted!
說得對！我來管 顯然不能信任你
It is your responsibility to make sure he has my number,
當他們和我過的時候 你有責任讓他知道我的號碼
when their with me, so you should've informed them
你早應該告訴他們
- that for these two weeks they call me. - They have to call their mother.
- 這兩個禮拜他們要打電話給我 - 他們得打電話給他們的媽媽
You know what I am not entertaining this discussion. Hello.
我不是開玩笑的，喂
This is my screw up.
這是我的責任
I'm entitled to screw up in my two weeks,
在我照顧他們的兩周 這都是我的責任
and you can screw up for the rest of the year.
你要負責過了這兩周再說
Right. You don't screw up. Okay fantastic.
對，你沒有責任，很好
Say goodbye to your mom guys.
兒子，跟媽媽說再見
- I'm sorry about this guys, Lenny. - I am right and you are wrong.
- 我真心覺得他們可憐，倫尼 - 我是對的，你錯了
Goodbye! Say goodbye to your mother.
再見！ 跟媽媽再會！
Say bye to mom. Come on. Say bye.
跟媽媽再會，快點，說再見！
- Bye mom. - We have got to seriously rush.
- 媽媽再見 - 我們得跑快點了
Sprint!
快！
Whoo! Fantastic guys.
喔！太棒了！
Alright, give me five.
哈哈，慶祝一下
What your looking for is a little white circle,
你們要找的是一個小白圈兒
its gonna appear in the upper right hand corner, okay.
它會出現在右上角，明白？
And it's going to appear for four frames long.
它會持續4幀的時間
Alright, film runs at 24 four frames a second,
電影每秒24幀
I don't know how long a human blink is, but do not blink,
我不知道眨一眨眼多長時間 但是你們千萬別眨眼
I want you focused intensely on that upper right hand corner.
我要你聚精會神盯著右上角看
That is a secret signal just for us, okay?
這是我們的秘密暗號，好麼？
- Alright, what are you looking for? - The white circle.
- 好的，你在找什麼？ - 白圈兒
And what are you going to do when you see it?
你看到以後要怎麼做？
- I'm gonna flip the button. - Alright.
- 我就按一下這個鈕 - 好的
You looking? Don't blink.
你在看麼？別眨眼
- Alright go. - No.
- 好了，按 - 不要
- Go! Go!
- 按，快按！
"Why doesn’t the state just, just put him away?"
「為什麼國家不把他帶走？」
Projection. Alright let's do it.
放映室 好的我們開始
How you guys doing? Comfortable?
你們在幹嘛？ 這樣舒服麼？
- No. - Yes.
- 不 - 舒服
Alright, you guys need anything I'm right in the booth.
好吧，你們要什麼的話 我就在房間
Right on the line, right on the arrow.
對齊邊線，放箭頭上
- On the arrow? - Yeah...
- 放箭頭上？ - 對…
- Let's do a test for starters. Okay? - Okay, one.
- 我們先印一張試試 - 好的，印一張
Yes!
來了！
Based on a true story. "Hey Lenny, get me a cup of water!"
根據真實故事改編 「喂，倫尼，給我拿杯水」
That's the boss. And that's dad, "OK OK."
那個是老闆 那是爸爸，「好的，好的」
Water. And that's the boss's cup.
水，這是老闆的杯子
And then he's going into the bathroom and peeing in the cup.
然後他走進浴室，往杯子塈縉
No description. Penis. Boss cup.
不用解釋了 小雞雞，老闆的杯子
Gulp gulp. "This tastes salty!"
咕嘟咕嘟，「這個好咸」
I can't believe he actually peed in the water.
我真不敢相信 他居然真的往水塈縉縣F
- OK, so now... - Let's do a thousand.
- 好了，現在… - 我們來印一千份
A thousand yeah.
好的，一千份
Maybe it's 999.
也許是999份吧
999. OK, print.
999份，印吧
Alright guys.
孩子們
What'd I say.
我說
- Sage jacket on. - Why this is the good part.
- 薩奇穿上外套 - 為什麼？正看到精彩處
We're going, put your jacket on, I'm not kidding, put your jacket on.
我們要走了，穿上外套 我不是開玩笑，穿上外套
Come on.
快點
Hey guys! Hey.
孩子們！
Guys come on.
孩子們快來
Sup, guys... what's going on...
小帥哥，怎麼了？
What's in the bags?
包堿O什麼？
Get 'em!
抓住！
It's going away!
飛走了！
- Hey! What is this? What is this? - I don't know.
- 那是什麼？ - 我不知道
Get over here! Get over here!
拿過來！拿過來！
- Jake, Jake, Jake... - Hey man.
- 傑克，傑克，傑克… - 啥事
What's cooking? You doing anything tonight?
最近忙啥呢？ 你今晚有事麼？
- Uh, no I was just a... - Alright,
- 沒有，我正要… - 正好
I got a proposition for you alright, I'll give you free reign over my place,
跟你商量件事 今晚你在我家隨便玩
use it as a studio, get some work done, you watch my kids for a few hours,
把它當工作室，在那兒做事 幫我帶幾個小時孩子
eat anything you want, and in exchange...
想吃什麼隨便拿 作為回報…
Here's that Kurtzman you've been Eyeing.
這是克魯澤曼的新片 你心心唸唸很久的
Come on. Do it.
過來吧
- Yeah definitely. - Far out.
- 好啊 - 太好了
Listen, I'm gonna take a shower. 45 minutes meet me at my place alright.
聽著，我先去沖個澡 過45分鐘來我家見我
Yeah, OK. 45.
好，過45分鐘
So you guys wanna do like, good guys bad guys?
你們要不要玩好人壞人？
Like everyman for himself.
就像其他人一樣
- Good guys bad guys. - Push it open!
- 好人壞人 - 把它打開
Jake. Jake. Look.
傑克，傑克，你看
This guy could be dead, or could be not.
這傢伙可能會死，也可能不會
Look what happened to his face. You guys should paint these.
看他臉怎麼了 你們肯定亂畫了
- No MSG. - OK, one, OK. You finished?
- 不加味精 - 好的，好的，沒其他需要了？
OK, you order spring rolls, and Coke a Cola, no MSG.
您點了春卷，一杯可樂，不加味精
- I was kidding. - Thank you.
- 我開玩笑的 - 謝謝
What's up?
笑什麼？
Nothing, I just, I haven't, I don't know. I haven't seen you for a little while.
沒什麼，只是，我不知道 我只是一會兒沒看到你
Your funny, your funny looking to me. You look unfamiliar.
你的滑稽，滑稽的樣子 你看起來和以前不一樣
Funny Looking. Your hair got.
看上去很搞笑，你的頭髮
- What, more gray? - Yeah.
- 怎麼，更灰了？ - 是的
- Yeah, there's less of it - There is less of it and it's grey...
- 是啊，還變少了 - 又少又灰
That's because Frey's constantly yanking it out.
那都要歸功於弗雷堅持不懈地拔
- Wow, that was fast. - Thank you.
- 好快 - 謝謝
Jesus.
老天爺
- You first.
- 先是您的
- That's incredible. - Yeah, your coke. Ice. No MSG.
- 真難以置信 - 是啊，您的可樂，冰的，不加味精
- Thanks. - Enjoy your meal.
- 謝謝 - 你們慢用
Thank you.
多謝
Oh! I had an Idea,
我有一個主意
how about all of us go upstate for a little while.
我們一起去鄉下玩怎麼樣？
Why don't we just get out of the city for a little while,
為什麼不暫時遠離城市
then it won't feel so hectic.
這樣就不會那麼累了
It's not going to be so chaotic up there's fall foliage...
也不會那麼混亂 那埵竟’a落葉
there's a lot of space for the kids to run around,
也有足夠的地方讓孩子們玩耍
they can do loops around the house.
他們可以繞著房子跑
Listen to me. Conceptually that is a wonderful idea,
聽我說，理論上講這個主意很好
but on every other level it is a horrible idea.
但從其他方面來講這主意很可怕
You understand that. I don't think you have any sense,
你知道麼？ 我不覺得你明白
what it's like for me right now, you know.
我現在的境況什麼樣
This is what it's like being inside my brain right now.
我腦子當中現在是這樣一番場景
Okay, just... just... just be a little bit more open,
好吧 只是…只是稍微再開放一點不好嗎
like next time we're all hanging out right.
下次我們一起出去的時候
- Yeah. - I just want you to a...
- 恩 - 我只是想讓你…
- What? - Just involve me a little bit more.
- 什麼？ - 稍微多考慮我一點
- Just, not even involve me... - Okay, okay...
- 甚至不能說是考慮… - 好，好…
Okay, alright I'm sorry.
好吧，對不起
- Oh, fuck! Come on. - Come on... no!
- 我靠，快點！ - 加油，噢不！
Fuck it! Forget it.
他媽的，算了吧！
I can't pee for such a long time you know.
我尿不了那麼長時間了
So Frey, we're gonna do it okay.
所以弗雷，我們不能失敗
Oh, cool! A fire truck.
好酷啊，一輛消防車
- Is that pee? - Yeah!
- 那是尿麼？ - 是的！
OK. OK.
好吧
Oh, yeah!
歐耶！
That's it.
畫完了
Frey! Help it! It's under a bump, quickly! We need to retreat!
弗雷，幫它一下，它碰到障礙了
- Hey! Oh! - OK, done, done.
- 嘿！噢！ - 好了，好了
Truce, truce.
投降，投降
Done.
好了
Alright.
好吧
Taxi!
出租車！
Well let's walk the tracks.
我們沿鐵軌走回家！
I have a better Idea.
我有個更好的主意！
- What's that? - I'll take a nap on the third rail,
- 什麼？ - 我在輸電軌道上睡一會兒
how bout that. Will you watch my stuff?
怎麼樣？ 你願不願意看著我的東西？
No, no, no. I'm actually serious. Let's walk the tracks.
不不不，我是認真的 我們沿鐵軌走回家
I'm actually serious too,
我也是認真的
I'm gonna take a nap on the third rail right there.
我要在輸電軌上睡一會兒
Yeah... that's gonna kill you. This is gonna be fun. Let's go.
是啊…這樣你會死的 很有趣的，我們走吧
Alright.
好吧
- After you. - With all do respect,
- 你先走 - 老實說
- that's a really stupid idea. - I think it's a great idea.
- 這真是個很蠢的主意 - 我覺得很好啊
- I still think your joking. - I think your a stupid idea.
- 我還是覺得你在開玩笑 - 你的主意才蠢呢
Go, I'll see you at the next station.
走，我到下一個車站等你
Sayonara.
再見！
- Leni! - Yeah?
- 倫尼！ - 恩？
Hey.
嘿
Up and at 'em. What's shaking man, how'd it go?
醒醒 怎麼樣？
Fine, it was fine, until I, I got peed on.
還好吧，直到我被尿噴了
That sucks.
該死
Well if it's any consolation, my night was a complete bust man.
如果非要說點什麼來安慰你 今晚我也過得一團糟
I completely wasted the fucking Kurtzman.
我惹毛了克魯澤曼
Yeah. Whatever.
是啊，無所謂了
Listen... please don't ask me to do this again.
聽著，以後別讓我幫這種忙了
It wasn't a favor man I paid you.
那不是幫忙，我付給你錢了
- Jesus. - Hey.
- 老天 - 喂
- What the fuck happened to you? - You mad at me.
- 你他媽怎麼了？ - 你對我發瘋了
For crying out loud.
真他媽響
Hello? Jeff you woke me up man, what's going on?
傑夫，你吵醒我了，什麼事？
No, no.
不，不行
That is not possible man. I've got my kids...
不可能，我家媮晹釩臚l呢…
OK, I understand you have two kids in the room,
我理解你家埵釣潃茷臚l
but we have about a hundred prints here, that need to be checked by tomorrow.
但是這兒大概有一百份
I'm sorry I can't even think straight.
對不起，我想不通
You know Chris and Rick are working their asses off right now,
克奡筒M塈J忙得不可開交
trying to get us ready for tomorrow.
想為明天做好準備
You know what, but that's not my problem... it's your problem!
但這不是我的問題
Jeff? Jeff?
傑夫？傑夫？
You know it was my problem earlier today,
今天早些時候確實是我的問題
I had to clean up a bunch of freaking comics
我得清理一大堆奇怪漫畫
that were strewn all over the theater, and I had to find people clean it up.
劇院堥麭B都是 我得找人來清理掉
You know what! That was my problem, and you know what else is my problem,
這是我的問題 你知道我還有什麼問題麼？
is when they run around this freaking booth like its a freaking playground.
他們跑到小房間的時候 它看起來就跟個操場一樣
Alright, I'll have my girlfriend watch the, alright, goodbye.
好，好，我讓我女朋友照看家，再見
Listen, listen. OK I have to pull an all nighter. OK.
聽著，我要去加夜班
OK. I can't watch the kids though.
行，但我不能照顧這倆孩子
Um, I don't think you understand, I'm going to lose my job,
你不明白 我工作要丟了
and I need somebody here to watch them when the wake up.
他們醒來的時候需要有人在這兒
Look, I would love to but I can't, I just can't.
我願意，但是不行，真是不行
I've got to work in the morning. I'm really, really sorry.
我明天早上還要上班 真的真的對不起
- I would love to watch the kids. - I'll be right back.
- 我很願意照看孩子 - 我馬上回來
Lenny? Where you going?
倫尼，你去哪兒？
- Yeah! - Jake. Listen, um,
- 誰啊！ - 傑克，聽著
I need you to watch my kids tomorrow morning man, it's a real emergency, OK?
我需要你明早照顧一下我孩子 真的是緊急情況，行不行？
No way.
沒門
Listen to me Jake, please. This is a dire situation OK,
聽我說，傑克，求你了 情況很糟糕
- I'm going to lose my job. - Sorry, no way.
- 我馬上要失業了 - 對不起，沒門
Is there anyway I can twist your arm man.
我要怎麼樣才能說服你？
Come here, quick.
快過來
Come. Leni.
過來，倫尼
Goddamn it!
我靠！
Listen, here's what we're gonna do.
聽著，我們要這麼干
- You see one of these? - Yeah. Sure.
- 有沒有看到這些 - 是啊
I take these when I want to sleep through the garbage trucks in the morning
我想在早上垃圾車的噪聲中睡著時 就吃這個
and just get an extra three hours rest, okay.
這樣就能再睡三個小時
- So we divide this up. - Okay.
- 我們把它掰開 - 好的
Give the kids a third each, and then we're good to go.
餵他們每人吃三分之一 然後我們就可以安心走了
I don't know if that's a good idea, their just little kids, I don't know.
我不知道這樣做好不好 他們只是孩子，我不知道
Listen to me, what's a worse idea is if they wake up and nobody's here.
聽我說 更壞的是他們醒來後發現這兒沒人
Do you understand that okay. They're gonna freak the fuck out.
明白麼？他們會抓狂的
This is a sedative.
這是鎮靜劑
- It's cool. - Okay.
- 很好 - 恩
Check it out, you see that? That's like an eighth of a pill.
仔細看，看到沒？ 差不多八分之一片
Okay, I think there may be a little bit too much in there.
恩，我覺得可能太多了
Alright, come on.
好了，過來
Come on!
來啊！
Alright buddy.
很好，夥計
OK, go back to sleep, go back to sleep.
睡吧，睡吧
Alright buddy.
很好
Lenny!
倫尼！
Alright guys. Let's do it.
夥計們，起床吧
Come one. Up.
快起床
Up!
起床啊
I know you guys can hear me, come on.
我知道你們聽見了，快起來
Alright. One... two... three.
好吧，一…二…三
Come on. Come on, I'm serious.
快起來，快，我說真的
Crunch! Crack! Come on guys.
砰！啪！ 快起來，兒子
Guys come on.
兒子，快！
Come on!
起來！
- Stephen! Holy shit. - Where are they?
- 斯提芬！我靠 - 他們在哪兒？
They're right over here.
他們就在那兒
They've just been out like this for the past...
他們已經這樣躺了…
Listen man, you know, I take one of these pills
每次我吃一顆藥
when I want to sleep for an extra two hours, you know.
能讓我多睡兩小時
Are you sure you only gave them an eighth?
你確定只給他們吃了八分之一片？
I chopped up a little bit...
我就捻起來一小撮
It was not more than that, it was a pinch!
肯定不會多於八分之一 就一小撮
I'm telling you a whole one knocks a full grown man out for two hours!
一整片只能讓成年人多睡兩小時
You got to back off.
別嘴硬了
Here, that was it, this is...
給你，就是這個
Is it possible it has something to do with the tap water?
會不會和自來水有關？
- I mixed it with tap water. - No! Just be quiet.
- 我用自來水沖藥的 - 不會！安靜一點
- Maybe the pills were expired? - Shut up! Stop it.
- 會不會是藥過期了？ - 閉嘴！
Their in what’s called stage for sleep.
他們正處於所謂的「睡眠階段」
- What is that? - It's like practically a coma.
- 什麼意思？ - 差不多是昏迷
But lucky for you they'll wake up from it.
但幸運的是，他們會醒過來
That means they're good. They're fine.
也就是說他們還好
- Yeah! They're not fine. - You are so lucky.
- 不！他們不好 - 你真幸運
I'm all fucked up man, I don't know.
我現在腦子一團亂，我不知道
I mean, honestly if I wasn't your friend I would've called the police.
我的意思是 如果我不是你朋友的話，我會報警
You know... I'm a doctor... I'm not supposed to be like.
…我是個醫生…我不該這樣
So they don't need to go to the hospital, they're okay just here.
他們不需要去醫院 這樣待著就好
So I don't have to tell... I don't have to tell their mother.
所以我不用告訴他們媽媽了
They're going to be fine, they'll wake up...
他們馬上就會好，會醒過來
Well I don't know when your talking to her.
我不知道你什麼時候告訴她好
It could be two days, it could be a week,
他們可能過兩天 或過一個禮拜醒過來
- it could be up to four weeks. - Holy shit!
- 最多一個月 - 我靠
It's not funny!
這不好笑！
We don't need to go to a hospital or anything like that.
我們不用去醫院或其他地方
- So I don't need to freak out right? - They should be fine.
- 所以我不用驚慌是麼？ - 他們會好起來的
Is this like dangerous, is there gonna be residual effects?
會不會有危險或者後遺癥？
Like I said, they're fine. I can't believe this.
我說過了，他們還好，真不敢相信
Alright, well thanks for coming in.
好吧，多謝你過來
Your welcome. I'm just glad everything's okay.
沒關係，我只慶幸一切還好
- So we don't have to freak out. - We don't have to freak out.
- 所以我們不必驚慌 - 我們沒必要抓狂
You just got to wait.
你只需要等等
I just, you know, I just have so much shit coming down at work,
我只是，只是工作中煩心事太多
I'm not thinking clearly, man you know. I really appreciate this.
我沒想清楚，但還是很感謝你
I just can't... I don't know what's wrong with you.
我只是，不知道你哪兒不對勁
If you weren't my friend I would've called the police.
如果你不是我朋友，我早報警了
...alright you said that twice now. - Thank you for coming by.
…你都說過兩遍了 - 謝謝你過來
You know that song. And what else did she do.
你知道那首歌的 她還做了什麼？
Of rainbows and flower... Rainbows and...
唱彩虹和花的 彩虹和…
Leslie Gould. So that was your apology to her?
萊斯利·古爾德 你就是這麼對她道歉的？
That was my apology, I mean I think that she... she accepted.
我就是這麼道歉的 我是說我覺得她會接受
Fuck!
操
- Shit! He's back. - What?
- 媽的！他回來了 - 啥？
He's back hang on.
他又回來轉悠了
Fuck!
媽的！
Shit.
靠
I'm more concerned with the guy screaming in this apartment.
我更關注在公寓埵y叫的傢伙
Do you see him?
看到他沒？
- Just pick up the bag. - OK, no, the bag has holes in it.
- 把袋子拎起來就好 - 好，不，袋子上有洞
- I have to get him in the jar. - He's more afraid of you.
- 我要把它引到罐子 - 它更害怕你
- Go in there. - Whoa. Put him in the thing.
- 進去了 - 哇，把它放堶
- OK. I'm gonna throw this out. - Okay go!
- 好了，我要把它扔掉 - 好，扔啊
Before we get into this. Why don't you just call the kids.
我們為什麼不去叫一叫孩子們呢？
Please, Stephen made it very clear... Listen to me.
斯提芬說得很清楚了 聽我講
He said. A minimum of two days right, so I don't want to like...
他說至少兩天 所以我不想…
That's why I'm here. I don't want to rack my brain worrying about it hour by hour.
所以我來你這兒了 我不想時時刻刻傷神煩這件事
I know, but then I... Just so that I could get it off my mind too,
我知道，但是…
just give them a call and make sure that
給他們打電話
their not still wondering around the apartment, like awake.
看看他們是不是已經醒了 在房間媔藕
- Alright. - And lost.
- 好的 - 然後迷路了
Hey guys! It's me!
兒子！是我！
There's no doubt in my mind that your asleep right now.
我相信你們現在還在睡著
But on the off chance that you woke up prematurely, here I am.
但是萬一你們提前醒了話 我在這
Pick up the phone.
過來接電話
If you hear my voice, pick up the phone.
如果聽到我聲音，就接電話
If you can hear me,
如果能聽到我，就接電話
Come on guys.
過來，兒子！
Alright I'm gonna count to three.
我數到三
And I'm just going to assume that you are asleep.
不然就只當你們還在睡
One one thousand, pick up the phone.
一 快接電話
Two one thousand.
二
I'll keep checking in. I love you. Bye.
我會常打電話來的 我愛你們，再見
But you were buying spray paint and that was for work.
你買了幹活用的噴漆
Yeah. I can put it on the tab and buy, you know, an overload of an amount
是啊，我把它列入購物清單 買一大堆
and I can kind of sneak in my own colors.
足夠換上自己喜歡的顏色
- For? - I go bombing.
- 為啥？ - 我要去「轟炸」
What does that mean?
什麼意思
Bombing. Like graffiti. You know, like that primitive...
轟炸，類似於塗鴉 就像老藝術家一樣
Really? Like, you write stuff or you draw pictures?
真的？你要寫東西？畫畫？
- I write rambo. On Sundays. - Rambo. You write that?
- 我禮拜天就去寫第一滴血 - 第一滴血？你寫那個？
- I usually like to go on Sundays- - Are there less cops maybe?
- 我經常星期天去 - 是不是那兒警察比較少？
Yeah, well they have that T.N.T. Tuesday night task-force.
他們有炸藥 就像週二晚間特戰隊一樣
Tuesdays and Thursdays there are more cops on the street.
週二週四的時候街上條子比平常多
- Hey, what's up, man? - What's happening?
- 怎麼了夥計？ - 發生什麼事？
- Lenny. - Hey. What's up, man?
- 倫尼 - 嘿，怎麼了？
- You mind if I join you guys? - No.
- 介不介意我加入你們？ - 不介意
Look, I don't wanna interrupt I'm just totally listless.
我不是想來打擾你們 我只是心情不好
I just wanna kill time. You know, I don't wanna go home yet...
只想消磨時間，我還不想回家
He's gonna tell us a story. He's a graffiti artist.
他要給咱講故事，他是塗鴉藝術家
I'm not sure if I'm supposed to say that.
我不知道該不該說
For Christ's sake.
看在基督的份上
- You can't even see it. - C'mon. It's fuckin' cold, man.
- 你都看不見 - 快點，好冷啊
Cut it out.
別玩了
For cyrin' out loud. Let me have this.
搞什麼，給我
No oil here. I don't know what that means.
沒油了 我不知道他什麼意思
It looks good, Lenny. Way to lay it on thick, man.
寫得不錯，倫尼 在拍你馬屁呢
Don't put my last name on there.
別把我的姓寫上去
Lenny! Run! Lenny! 50. Run Lenny!
倫尼，快跑，快跑！
- Oh, fuck. - NYPD, let me see your hands!
- 我操 - 警察，舉起手來！
- Let me see your hands! - Whoa, whoa, listen!
- 舉起手來！ - 聽我說！
- I didn't do anything.
- 我啥都沒干
Up against the wall. Let me see your hands.
趴在牆上 舉起手來
- Hey! I'm not resisting. - Let me see your hands.
- 喂！我沒有反抗！ - 給我看你的手！
- I didn't do anything! - Stop movin'.
- 我啥都沒幹！ - 別動！
- First of all- - I don't wanna hear your mouth! Stop movin'!
- 首先 - 我不想聽你講話，別動！
- I'm not resisting. - What do you have on you?
- 我沒有反抗！ - 你身上帶的什麼？
Listen to me. I was writing something nice.
聽我講，我在寫一些好的…
- What'd you have on you back there!? - Do I have anything on me? Alright.
- 你後面藏著什麼？ - 我身上有東西麼？好吧！
I'm not resisting. For the record, I'm not resisting!
我沒有反抗 給我作證，我沒反抗！
Let's go.
進去
Line up right over here by the window. Back against the wall.
在窗邊排好隊 背靠牆
Back against the wall!
靠著牆！
I'm tryin' to figure out what needs to happen
我想搞清楚，我們要做點啥
before we can get back out on the street.
才能出去
- Well, Dad, we need to- - Don't be a dick, alright?
- 哦，老爹，我們需要… - 別做慫蛋，行麼？
We'll probably see a judge in the next twenty-four hours,
我們在未來24小時內可能被送上法庭
- I'm assuming. - It's gonna be a while.
- 我只是假設 - 還有一段時間
Since it's the weekend we're definitely gonna be in here a little longer.
因為是週末 我們肯定會在這兒待久一點兒
I don't want the fuckin' sandwich! Cut it out!
我不要什麼屌三明治，扔了
Leni. It's me. This is a bonafide emergency.
樂尼，是我 我碰到點急事
So, I don't know where you are,
我不知道你在哪兒
I don't know why you're not picking up your phone.
也不知道你為什麼不接電話
That was my last quarter. I'm kinda freakin' out.
我身上只有一個硬幣了 我快崩潰了
I need you to please go up to thirty-fifth street
所以聽到留言後麻煩你去35大街
and check on the kids as soon as you get this.
看看孩子們有沒有醒
I have to see a judge apparently and that might happen at nine in the morning,
我得去受審，可能是上午九點
it might happen at eleven in the morning... goodbye.
也可能是十一點…再見
Anyone have another quarter?
還有沒有人有硬幣？
Why don't you call collect?
你幹嘛不打對方付費的電話？
- You want my sandwich? - No. I'm good, thanks.
- 要不要三明治？ - 不用，謝謝
Hey buddies.
你們好啊！
Dad, can you turn down the music?
爸，能不能把音樂調低一點兒？
Frey! Oh God!
弗雷，天啊！
Sage! You're awake! Oh my God!
薩奇，你醒了！ 老天爺！
Listen, listen, we overslept, we're late for school.
聽著，聽著，我們睡晚了，上學要遲到了
We have five minutes. We overslept. It's my fault. It's my fault!
還有五分鐘，我們都睡晚了 是我的錯，我的錯
- This isn't the right way. - Right way where?
- 我們走的路對麼？ - 去哪兒的路？
To school.
學校
Well guess what? That's 'cause we're not going to school.
知道為啥麼？我們不去學校
- Where are we going? - C'mon, fuckers! Jump up.
- 那我們去哪兒？ - 來吧小子，快走！
Run!
跑起來！
- It seems to easy... - Alright, go. I'll catch you.
- 看起來太簡單了 - 走吧，我會抓住你們的
You know what'll happen if you fall over.
你知道如果你們掉下來會怎樣？
I'll race you down, Sage. Ready, go.
我會跟著你，薩奇，預備，走
Hey, hey. Okay. C'mon guys.
喂喂，加油，兒子！
C'mon, slowpoke.
快點，慢吞吞的
- Daddy? - What?
- 爸！ - 怎麼？
Get down.
坐下
C'mon, dad!
快點，爸爸！
Frey, Frey, Frey come here. Great. It's great. It's fortifying.
弗雷，弗雷，過來！ 這真鼓舞人心
Stop, guys. C'mon.
停，快停
I want you to appreciate what you're seeing.
我想讓你們領會看到的東西
Isn't there something? Give me one detail from each window
有沒有什麼特別的東西？ 給我講講每個窗口看到的細節
and then we can move on. You each have to say one detail.
然後往下看 你們倆都要講點啥
Realistic clouds.
雲彩
Okay, good. Realistic clouds. That's one. You?
很好，雲彩 這是一點，你看到什麼？
- Red flowers. - Okay, red flowers. That's good.
- 紅花 - 紅花，很好
Okay, one detail out of each window and then you're aloud to move on.
好的，每個窗口講一個細節 然後你們能繼續往下看
Beautiful background.
漂亮的背景
Beautiful background. Okay, that's sorta generic, but it's passable.
漂亮的背景，講得很粗略，但能通過
It means, you know, it's not the most colorful description.
這不是最精彩的描述
What's happening, guys?
怎麼了，兒子？
- Is that real? - Yep.
- 那是真的麼？ - 是啊
You know I killed one just like this in the bathroom the other day.
我有一天在衛生間打死了一隻一樣的
- Did it suck your blood? - Actually, it didn't suck my blood
- 它吸你的血了麼？ - 其實沒有
but I used one of your old sweatshirts to sop it up.
但我用了你們一件舊汗衫去撲它
- Was there a lot of blood? - Oh, yeah.
- 是不是流了很多血？ - 是啊
- That would suck all of your blood out. - There native to New York.
- 它會吸光你們的血 - 它們是紐約原住民
Yeah that would suck all of your blood out.
是啊，那會吸光你的血
Are those real?
那些是真的麼？
Yeah, they breed in the sewers. Nah, it's made out of wax I think.
是啊，它們在下水道堛齯j 我想它們是用蠟做的
They magnify it so you can see all the details. That's incredible.
他們把它放大了，這樣你們才能看清
- Heads under. - Daddy, you know that mosquito
- 低下頭 - 爸，你認得那只蚊子麼？
you said you killed that we saw in the museum?
你說我們在博物館見到的那只 是你打死的
I was kidding. That was a joke.
我開玩笑的
Remember today you were making all sorts of jokes.
今天你們開了好多玩笑 記得嗎？
Remember at the museum you said I looked like the monkey.
記不記得你們在博物館說我長得像猴子
- No. - Well, I was joking too.
- 不記得 - 我也開個玩笑
Yeah, but-
是啊，但是…
Mosquitoes do not exist at that size.
沒有那麼大的蚊子
They don't exist in this apartment at that size.
我們家不會有這麼大的蚊子
Only in the world of jokes are there mosquitoes that big.
只有在童話世界堣~有這麼大的蚊子
- Alright, guys, dunk your heads. - But was it slimy?
- 好了，兒子，泡一下頭 - 不會太黏麼？
Under, under, under.
低下頭，低下
C'mon, seriously guys dunk your heads please.
快點，快泡一泡頭髮，兒子
- I did. - I know you did.
- 我泡了 - 我知道
Please. Take a page from your brother's book.
跟你弟弟學一學
- Mom's name is Paige. - That's right. That's correct.
- 媽媽叫佩吉 - 對哦，是啊
Alright,
好吧
you don't leave me any choice.
我沒得選
Dad, every time I close my eyes I see the mosquito and you said
爸爸，每次我閉上眼
you'd turn on the lights, so can you please turn on the lights?
開開燈，能不能開一下燈？
It's just gonna make it harder to fall asleep.
那樣會更睡不著的
Can you please turn on the light, I don't care.
能不能開一下燈，我不在乎
- Yeah, can you turn on the light. - Alright, alright.
- 是啊，能不能開一下燈？ - 好吧，好吧
I don't want the mosquito to come and suck my blood out.
我可不想蚊子過來吸光我的血
You realize, guys, that mosquitoes are drawn to light.
兒子，蚊子會被光吸引的
So, if anything this is just gonna make it scarier.
如果真有大蚊子，開燈會更糟
And harder for us to fall asleep.
而且我們都睡不著
'Night dad. 'Night dad, 'night Sage.
「晚安爸爸」 「晚安薩奇」
Alright, goodnight guys.
好吧，晚安
When are we gonna see you again?
我們過多久能再見你？
Soon, very soon.
很快
Five days?
五天？
- Well, not five days. - I bet in a year.
- 不是 - 我猜一年
- Less than a year. - No.
- 不到一年 - 不要
- Yes, I mean. - C'mon guys.
- 就是一年 - 快點兒子
Yes we'll see in you in less than a year.
我們用不了一年就能再見你了
- Hey. - Sorry, I'm late.
- 嗨 - 對不起我遲到了
Hi, I love you guys. I missed you.
兒子，我想你們了，媽媽愛你們
Listen, I got movie tickets. We gotta go.
我買了電影票，快走吧
- Alright, go to your mom. - Let me get a taxi.
- 兒子，去你們媽媽那兒 - 我去打輛車
C'mon, go to your mother. I know you guys don't wanna go, c'mon!
快去媽媽那兒 我知道你們不想走
Run! I'm serious, you're late. Go.
快走，我說真的，你們要遲到了
- Here's a taxi, you guys! - Seriously, no joke, it's time.
- 有出租車了 - 真的，快遲到了
- They don't wanna leave. - I got treats.
- 他們不想走 - 我請客
- Listen, say good bye to your dad. - Bye, dad.
- 跟爸爸說再見 - 再見，爸爸
- Just wave to your father. - Hey Frey, you know what?
- 跟他再見 - 弗雷，你知道麼？
That's what.
沒什麼了
- Wave to your dad. - The bag!
- 跟爸爸揮揮手 - 包沒拿
- Hey! Hey!
- 包！ - 喂！
Sorry.
對不起
Hey, hey. What do we have? Got some nice wood here.
喂，看我們找到啥了 上好的木料
- Look, you don't see this everyday. - Dale, c'mon.
- 不是每天都能碰到的 - 戴爾，過來
This is good. I can do anything with this.
這木頭不錯，啥都可以做
- Help me take it to the car. - It's junk.
- 幫我搬到車上去 - 那是廢料
No, it's good, I can do anything with it.
不，那是好料，啥都可以做
It's junk. Check it out. It's cheap wood. You see that?
那是垃圾，看 便宜貨，看到沒？
- Relax, man. You're gonna ruin it. - Ruin it? It's a piece of shit!
- 輕點兒，都踩爛了 - 踩爛？本來就是爛貨
Relax, man!
輕點兒
Leni.
樂尼
I am not angry. I am frustrated.
我不生氣，只是很沮喪
And very confused. I would like to just hear from you.
還很困惑，我只想聽聽你的聲音
If you would like me to stop calling you I would like to know that.
如果你不想我打電話來 我以後就不打了
I keep saying, the kids are not here anymore.
孩子們不在我這兒了
I have the free space,
現在家堛聾F
I have the mental space to be more considerate.
我也想明白了點
I don't know.
我不知道
Please, just call me and say hello
求你了，給我回個電話吧
or call me to tell me to stop calling you.
或者打個電話告訴我 別再給你打電話了
Fuck!
靠
Hey! Hey! What the fuck are you doing, man!? Hey!
喂喂，你他媽去哪兒？
Hey, quick, you hear that? Frey, Frey?
聽到沒？ 弗雷，弗雷？
Sage? Sage?
薩奇，薩奇？
Sage! What's shakin'? What's happening, kiddo?
薩奇，怎麼了？
Very good. Listen, will you put your mom on?
很好，能不能讓媽媽接電話？
Will you put your mom on for me?
能不能讓媽媽接一下電話？
Okay. Here she is. It's dad.
好吧，她在 是爸爸
Lenny?
倫尼？
Well, you know, it's six o'clock, I'm making dinner. What's up?
都六點了，我在做晚飯，你有事嗎？
Do this part again.
這部分再彈一遍
I've got Carmen coming tomorrow...
明天卡門要過來
No, no, but tomorrow is a half-day and I've got plans to take the kids
不是，但是明天是半日制
to see my folks this weekend. Okay? So it's not gonna happen.
我這週末計劃帶孩子去看音樂會 所以，不可能
It's a half day. Right. And I have paid Carmen in advance.
是半天，我也預先付錢給卡門了
She's coming to get the kids so it's not gonna work.
她會過來接孩子，所以不行
I understand that you miss the kids, that's great, but frankly,
我知道你想念孩子，這很好，但老實說…
you're lucky you even see the kids.
你能看到他們就該慶幸了
You are. Because I hear the stories.
對，因為我聽說你的事了
You know, I could easily get full custody with these kids.
我很容易就能爭取到孩子的全部撫養權
The stories that I've heard with all your weirdo friends.
我從你的損友那兒聽來的
These are little kids, it's completely inappropriate what you do with them.
他們只是小孩，你這麼做肯定是不恰當的
I know you're the father, but you know what?
我知道你是他們爸爸，但是…
You're not a great father all the time. And you certainly were not that great
你不是一個稱職的父親 而且在照看他們的兩周
when you had them for the last two weeks.
你也做得不好
It's not gonna happen, my food is getting burnt and over done here,
不可能，我的菜要燒糊了，就這樣吧
I've got to go.
我要走了
Okay, I'll see you. No. Goodbye.
好的，再見
Have you done anything? No. You haven't done anything.
你們有沒有做什麼？ 沒有，你們什麼都沒做
This is homework that's due tomorrow. You see? It's double sided, do it.
家庭作業明天之前必須作完 是雙面的，快做
Okay? Frey, we're gonna eat in five minutes, okay?
明白麼？弗雷，我們過五分鐘吃飯
So just hang in there.
繼續做
Frey! Frey!
弗雷！弗雷！
Frey!
弗雷！
Carmen! Como estas?
卡門！你好！
- Como esta usted? - Cuanto tiempo!
- 你好嗎？ - 很好
Mucho tiempo.
好久不見
How you doin' buddy? Surprise!
你好麼？驚喜吧！
- Hay una problemo. - Si, que paso?
- 有個問題 - 怎麼了？
Paige made a big mistake. Change of plans.
佩吉搞錯了，她改了計劃
I am taking the boys, I'm gonna give them
我來接孩子，我會給他們做一頓好吃的
a nice home-cooked meal today, I'm gonna return them.
然後把他們送回去
- I'm worried- - No, no, don't be worried.
- 我擔心… - 不不不，別擔心…
She gave me the money. It was just a mistake. Please.
她給我錢了，只是弄錯了
You know I'm responsible for them.
我得負責照顧他們
How you doin' buddy? Where's your brother?
你好麼，哥哥呢？
- Be good with daddy. - Say goodbye to Carmen.
- 去爸爸那兒要乖乖的 - 跟卡門再見
Alright, guys.
好了，兒子
Check it out.
看！
Alright we're almost ready for the chicken, guys. Alright?
我們差不多準備好了
I made a list. Where is it?
我列了張菜單，在哪兒呢？
We need some groceries. Sage, come over here.
我們缺點東西，薩奇，過來
- You're in charge. - What are we having for dinner?
- 你有任務了 - 我們晚飯吃什麼？
- We're having Lenny surprise. - Oh god.
- 給你們倫尼的驚喜 - 天啊
Chicken Lennini! Listen to me. This is a grocery list.
「倫尼雞」，聽我說，這是購物單
Read it back to me.
念給我聽
Milk, cream, orange juice, apple juice, peppercorn, salt-
牛奶，奶油，橙汁 蘋果汁，胡椒粉，鹽…
I don't want you going to the Korean place on the corner, alright?
別去街角那家韓國店，知道麼？
- It's a rip-off. - Where else would we go?
- 那是家黑店 - 那我們去哪兒？
...and you're gonna make a left, then you're gonna make a right-
…先左轉，然後右轉…
this is how we save money- then you're gonna make a right.
我們這麼做是要省錢，然後再右轉
You're gonna go to the big supermarket. Alright? This is fifty-five dollars.
去大超市，明白了？給你55塊錢
- I'll take it. - I got it.
- 我來拿 - 我拿到了
You're in charge of the money.
你負責保管錢
You're in charge of picking out the items. Teamwork, guys.
你負責挑東西，兒子，這是團隊協作
Alright, go. Twenty-ninth street and third avenue.
好了，走吧 二十九街第三街道
Bye, dad.
爸爸再見
Frey, Frey!
弗雷，弗雷！
Look, fruit snacks. They're my favorite.
看，水果蛋糕 我最喜歡吃了
- They have real fruit in them. - Toss 'em in, I guess.
- 堶扈u的有水果 - 放進去吧
Rosemary, rosemary. Crushed rosemary?
迷迭香，碎迷迭香
- Crushed or leaves? - Leaves.
- 拿碎屑還是葉子？ - 葉子
- Why leaves? - It looks nicer.
- 為什麼拿葉子？ - 看著好一點
- Hey! - Hey, dad!
- 嘿 - 嘿，爸爸！
Quick! Catch it! C'mon guys.
快點，兒子
- Come on in. Guys, come on in. - What's happening?
- 進來 - 怎麼了？
Listen to me, okay? Listen to me, very carefully, alright?
聽我說，認真聽我說！
This is a surprise. We are moving,
這是個驚喜，我們要搬家了
we have ten minutes to bring everything down to thirty-sixth street.
我們有十分鐘來把所有東西 搬到三十六大街
- What do you mean we're moving!? - Just what I said.
- 你說我們要搬了是什麼意思 - 就那個意思
We are moving to a much bigger apartment.
我們要搬去大房子
- What about the TV? - What about the sofa?
- 那電視機怎麼辦？ - 沙發呢？
Listen to me! We have ten minutes to go downstairs
聽我說，我們有十分鐘時間下樓
to a truck that is going to move us to a bigger apartment, okay?
到一輛搬家車上
I like this apartment!
我喜歡這個房子
You are embarrassing me in front of Mark.
你們讓我在馬克面前很尷尬
You are embarrassing yourselves
而且讓自己也很難堪
Lenny, this is a really weird situation.
倫尼，這個情況真的很難搞
I gotta get out of here. Hey guys. It's good to see you again.
我得走了，孩子們再見
I knew you when you were this big
你們這麼小的時候我就認識你們了
and you when you were just pretty much a thought.
那時候你們很可愛
- Mark, ten minutes. - No, I'm gone man.
- 馬克，等我十分鐘 - 不行，我要走了
Listen guys, we'll catch up the next time your dad's not moving.
孩子們，我下次來，你們爸爸不走了
Mark, mark. Do not do this to me. Please, do not do this to me.
馬克，馬克，別這樣，求你了，別這樣
Ten more minutes!
就十分鐘
You're really gonna wanna take your hand off. No more.
把手拿開，我不等了
- You've been a saint. - Yeah, well. Later.
- 你人那麼好 - 是啊，再見
Alright guys, change of plans. We are down to three.
好了，孩子們，計劃改變 我們三個人搬
I seriously need your cooperation. We have to work as a team.
我需要你們的協助，我們要團隊協作
- No! - Pick up a box, hold a box.
- 不要 - 拿一個箱子
Hold this box, alright.
拿著這個箱子
I got all your toys in here, okay?
你們的玩具都在堶
We're only taking he essentials now and guess what I considered an essential?
我們只帶重要的東西？ 知道什麼是重要的麼？
The games.
我們的秘密
Give me a box. Give me a box!
給我個箱子
What do you look so happy for? I see you smiling.
你怎麼這麼高興？ 我看到你在笑
I see you smiling! C'mon.
我看到你笑了
Alright guys.
好了，孩子們
Hey, hey, hey. Alright, thanks man.
喂喂！謝謝
- What's with the fridge? - I told you.
- 除了冰箱還有啥？ - 我告訴過你了
- I'm moving everything, man. - But what's with the fridge?
- 我所有的東西 - 那除了冰箱還有啥？
You just told me you, a couple boxes and that was it.
你剛告訴我還有一堆箱子
Just open the back for me, alright? Alright guys. Up and at 'em.
幫我開一下車廂門吧
And we're off.
我們出發了
Will you please hold on?
抓緊車好麼？
Thank you.
謝謝
This is pretty awesome, huh?
真刺激
Hey! Watch it!
喂，小心！
Hold on! Will you hold on to the thing!
抓好！你能不能抓好護欄？
Jesus Christ. Hold on. I said hold on.
天啊，我說讓你抓好的
I'm holding on!
我抓好了
Will you watch your driving man, I'm not kidding!
你會不會開車啊，我不是跟你開玩笑
That's it. You or anybody does not tell me how to drive.
我告訴你，誰都別來教我怎麼開車
Oh, come on man. For cryin' out loud.
哎，別激動嘛
- Get your stuff out. - Listen to me, I apologize.
- 把你東西拿下來 - 聽我說，對不起
- I got nothing to say. - This is not a personal thing.
- 沒什麼好說的了 - 這不是你的錯
The kids were bouncing all over the place.
孩子們一直在跳來跳去
- Get these things out. - Oh, give me a fuckin break!
- 把東西拿出來 - 你他媽給我次機會
You alright? You alright?
你還好吧？你呢？
Come on!
跟上！
Come on, guys! Here, three please.
快點，兒子 三個人
- Frey, help! - Just keep it.
- 弗雷，幫我一下 - 拿好
Could you open the service door for me?
能不能幫我開一下門？
Thank you.
謝謝
- I'm not going. - Help. Help!
- 我不走了 - 幫我一下！
I'm not going to.
我不要
Sage!
薩奇！
That's fine. Here, this way.
很好，這邊！
Forget it, just forget it.
別管了
Get the boxes on.
把箱子拿上來
Frey, I need you to cooperate right now.
弗雷，我希望你配合點兒
This is all gonna be over in five minutes, okay?
過五分鐘就好了
- No! - C'mon, I'm not kidding.
- 不要！ - 快點，我不是開玩笑！
- Get off! - Goddamn it. Alright, we're ready to go.
- 放我下來！ - 我靠，好了，走吧！
Get off!
放我下來！
Stop it. I'm not kidding. Listen to me...
別吵，聽我講
Good afternoon, if you’re standing,
下午好 如果您是站著的乘客
hold on please, while the cabin’s in motion.
請您在啟動時站穩扶好